[Music]
[音乐]
I'm a pretty excited to see that so many
看到这么多，我感到非常兴奋
of you show up for a session that
你们中的一个参加会议
promises to be boring so I'll leave the
一定会很无聊，所以我会离开
excitement with me and give you the
让我兴奋，给你
boring stuff and we'll see where we get
无聊的东西，我们会看到我们去哪里
from from here now I'm pretty sure you
从现在开始我很确定你
all have these moments in your in your
所有人中都有这些时刻
your career or your maybe hopefully
您的事业或您的希望
daily life where you you've made some
你做了一些的日常生活
application and you want to you want to
应用程序，并且您想要
test some stuff right you want to try
测试一些您想尝试的东西
out some new technologies and try
找出一些新技术并尝试
everything that you find there's
您发现的所有东西
probably a lot of talks you've seen
您可能已经看过很多讲座
today and yesterday that you want to try
今天和昨天你想尝试
out so what you do is you you build
出来，所以你要做的就是你建立
something you run it and it combines
你运行它的东西，它结合了
everything you could find right it does
您可以找到的所有正确功能
facial recognition to find out the mood
面部识别找出心情
that you currently have then scans the
您当前拥有的然后扫描
entire internet streams all of the pages
整个互联网流所有页面
and information they can find to see
他们可以找到的信息和信息
what kind of greeting is best for the
什么样的问候最适合
mood that you are currently in and
您当前所处的心情，
you're trying that you're putting some
您正在尝试放入一些
for the sake of it some spring wet flux
为此，一些春季湿润的助焊剂
just because you can and then it outputs
只是因为你可以然后它输出
yes right HelloWorld you're so proud and
是的，您好，HelloWorld很自豪，
you're really excited and you're ready
你真的很兴奋，你已经准备好了
to get this into production well
使它顺利进入生产
unfortunately production is not really a
不幸的是，生产并不是真正的
place for excitement right production is
兴奋权生产的地方是
a place where everything has to be
一个一切都必须存在的地方
boring otherwise it's your phone ringing
无聊，否则就是你的电话响了
of excitement in the middle of the night
在半夜兴奋
right when there's fires ready to be
当有火灾准备发生时
extinguished and stuff like that so this
熄灭之类的东西，所以这
is the boring stuff right you need
是您需要的无聊的东西吗
boring stuff to get it running in
无聊的东西让它运行
production and make sure that it stays
生产并确保其停留
running in production now if you've seen
如果您已经看到，现在可以在生产中运行
other talks with me you know that I love
与我的其他谈话你知道我爱
layered architecture and recently I came
分层架构，最近我来了
across a slightly different name for it
略有不同的名称
and I thought I like the absurdity of
我以为我喜欢
the of the name it's the universal BBC
它的名称是通用BBC
architecture and it has nothing to do
建筑，它无关
with the broadcasting organisation in
与广播组织在
the UK I hope and it's basically books
我希望是英国，基本上是书籍
books cylinder right the cylinder stores
书筒右筒存放
stuff and there's some boxes in front of
东西，前面有一些盒子
it because we want to separate concerns
因为我们要分开关注点
right so we do not want to put it
对，所以我们不想把它放
one box we put it in - because that
我们把一个盒子放进去-因为那
helps us build better software
帮助我们构建更好的软件
I guess unfortunately it doesn't and the
我猜很不幸，事实并非如此，
software we build ends up in the
我们构建的软件最终出现在
infamous big ball of mud which is
臭名昭著的大泥球
obviously not mud now of course nowadays
如今当然显然现在不泥泞
you can't come up with one big ball of
你不可能拿出一个大球
mud so what we do nowadays we have a new
泥浆，所以我们今天要做的是
style of architecture which is micro
微观的建筑风格
services we micro service all the things
服务我们微服务一切
so we have our little bbc's and we make
所以我们有我们的小英国广播公司，我们
them a bit smaller which I deploy lots
他们有点小，我部署很多
of them what could possibly go wrong
其中可能会出问题的地方
and our little BBC boxes are now
现在我们的BBC小盒子
connected and we separate some more
连接，我们分开了一些
concerns in in my experience seemingly
根据我的经验看来
randomly but all these concerns are
随机，但所有这些担忧都是
split all over and that's that's
分裂全部，那就是
fantastic now the problem is if you take
太棒了，现在的问题是，如果您服用
the design principles that deliver you a
为您提供设计理念
big bowl of mud and then increase the
大碗泥然后增加
number of deployment units of that
该部署单元的数量
design principle you get a big messy
设计原理你会很乱
let's call it just right it's let's
让我们称它为“拉屎吧”
call it what it is let's not be so what
叫它是什么，让我们不要这样
we need to do instead is focus on
我们要做的是专注于
increasing modularity first now there's
首先增加模块化，现在有
been some talks about modularity or
关于模块化的一些讨论或
modulus there's been some talks before
模数之前有一些谈话
so it's this is not a new topic right
所以这不是一个新话题
this is something that we should really
这是我们应该真正做到的
focus on so first we try to build
专注于所以我们首先尝试建立
something that is nicely structured
结构良好的东西
obviously not a big bowl of mud and as
显然不是一大碗泥
soon as we've proven to ourselves that
一旦我们向自己证明
we can do that then we can increase the
我们可以做到，然后我们可以增加
number of deployment units and go there
部署单元的数量并去那里
which is the nice colorful land of micro
这是微妙的美丽土地
services where we all want to be this is
我们都想成为的服务是
where promises are delivered right not
没有兑现承诺的地方
the bottom one unfortunately there are
不幸的是最下面的一个
some dark forces of evil in our projects
我们项目中一些邪恶的黑暗力量
that force us down back into the big
迫使我们回到了大世界
pile of in the corner
在角落里的一堆
and these are typically technical debt
这些通常是技术债务
caused by generally managers saying I
一般经理说我
want all of this stuff by tomorrow and
希望到明天所有这些东西，
don't you just work faster just think
你不只是更快地工作只是想
harder be smarter I don't know just try
变得更聪明我不知道只是尝试
something but I need it by tomorrow
有些东西，但是明天我需要
those are all kinds of forces that take
这些是各种各样的力量
you down into that and we need to fight
你陷入困境，我们需要战斗
those forces right we need every tool in
这些力量对，我们需要所有工具
our toolbox that we can get to to help
我们可以提供帮助的工具箱
us stay up there now I'm a very firm
我们现在待在那里我非常坚定
believer of the micro-services journey
微服务之旅的信徒
and that journey always starts with an
那旅程总是以
idea right you have a concept you want
想法正确，您有想要的概念
to build something it might be an
建立一些东西可能是
existing application that's finally that
现有的应用程序终于
case you're probably lucky because you
如果你可能很幸运，因为你
know more or less what you want to build
或多或少地知道您想要建造什么
and your ambition generally some or
而你的志向通常是
microservices right you can see the
可以看到微服务
services already but that journey over
服务已经存在，但是那段旅程
there is pretty dangerous right there's
那里很危险
a dangerous land in between and you're
介于两者之间的危险土地
very likely to get lost and get stuck in
很可能迷路并陷入困境
that distributed ball of mud thing so
散布泥球的东西，所以
the journey should be go to this
旅程应该去这个
structured monolith first prove to
结构化整体结构首先证明
yourself that you can build the
你自己，你可以建立
application then you can split out some
应用程序，然后您可以拆分出一些
of the components or build new
组件或新建
components separate of that slowly and
组件分开缓慢
steadily and then move on forwards and
稳步前进，然后前进
maybe then you can really go to this
也许那你真的可以去这个
promised land of service hopefully by
希望通过服务承诺的土地
then it's pretty well constructed unless
那么它的构造很好，除非
better than it is right now to be able
比现在更好
to achieve that there's this concept
要实现有这个概念
that we love at our exonic location
我们喜欢在我们的外显子位置
transparency and it's the principle that
透明度，这是原则
components within our application are
我们应用程序中的组件是
completely unaware of the location of
完全不知道位置
the other components that it
它的其他组件
communicates with right because in that
与权利沟通，因为在那
case we do not need to change any of the
在这种情况下，我们无需更改任何
logic that we have if we were to take
我们要采取的逻辑
one of these components split it out or
这些组件之一将其拆分或
split it out of the monolith obviously
将其从整体中分离出来
there's some technical glue that you
有一些技术胶水
need to do right there's some some
需要做的正确一些
configuration problem probably that you
配置问题可能是你
need to do to make sure that the
需要做的是确保
communication
通讯
can actually take place right
可以实际发生
communication within a single JVM is
单个JVM中的通信是
pretty simple we all know that it tends
很简单，我们都知道它倾向于
to get infinitely harder when you have
拥有时变得更加困难
to cross JVM boundaries so messaging is
跨越JVM边界，因此消息传递是
a very important concept in micro
微观上非常重要的概念
services right and we all know of events
服务权利，我们都知道事件
right events are in general interpreted
正确的事件通常被解释为
as a notification that something
通知某事
relevant happened in general they have
他们一般都有相关的经历
past tense then they just describe a
过去式，然后他们只描述一个
fact there's no way you can deny that
事实上，您无法否认
fact it happened and you're better deal
事实上发生了，你最好
with it and they follow a typical pub
用它，他们跟随一个典型的酒吧
shop kind of pattern but they're not the
商店的模式，但它们不是
only type of message that there is
仅有的消息类型
between micro sources and it doesn't
在微资源之间，它不会
matter and really matter how you
很重要，真的很重要
implement them conceptually you'll also
从概念上实施它们，您还将
have commands and queries you also have
有命令和查询，你也有
messages that are an indication of one
表示一个的消息
component to another that I expect you
我希望你的另一个组成部分
to do something I expect you at the
去做我期望你做的事情
state of the system to have change after
之后的系统状态会发生变化
you've executed this command as opposed
您执行了相反的命令
to what it is now and then there's the
到现在是什么，然后有
other one there's the query and the
另一个有查询和
query is I have a need for information
查询是我需要信息
and I know another component has the
我知道另一个组件具有
information I need so be very careful
我需要的信息，所以要非常小心
that an event and a message are not the
事件和消息不是
same thing write a message is the that's
同一件事写一条消息是
a parent stereotype of all the all the
所有的父母的刻板印象
types of messages they're commands the
他们所命令的消息类型
events and the queries that you can have
事件和您可以拥有的查询
now these three messages follow
现在，这三个消息如下
different routing patterns when a
不同的路由模式时
command goes to a single destination
命令转到单个目标
there's a side-effect that is caused by
有一个副作用是
that commander you probably want to get
你可能想得到的那个指挥官
some notifications from okay or not okay
正常或不正常的一些通知
back to to let you know whether your
回到以让您知道您是否
intent has been follow up and followed
意图已经跟进并遵循
up upon is that even English not sure
甚至是英语也不确定
the queries on the other hand they are
另一方面，它们是
there are sent somewhere and then the
有发送到某个地方，然后
sender is probably waiting hopefully
发送者可能正在等待
there's no thread waiting but at least
没有线程在等待，但至少
conceptually it's waiting for a response
从概念上讲，它在等待回应
it needs information so it waits for
它需要信息，所以它在等待
that information to become available
该信息变得可用
before it can move on
在继续前进之前
and there's some interesting things you
还有一些有趣的事情
can do with queries you can do scat
可以做你可以做的查询
together you can send a query to many
您可以一起向许多人发送查询
components gather all the answers do
组件收集所有答案
some reduction function on it and take
一些减少功能，并采取
the answer that you like most for
您最喜欢的答案
example I want to get the price of
例如我想得到的价格
products you get all sorts of prices and
您可以得到各种价格的产品
given that I'm Dutch my natural
鉴于我自然是荷兰人
reduction function is to take the
还原功能是取
cheapest one
最便宜的
and that's the price that the product
那就是产品的价格
takes so let's go to a little demo and
因此，让我们去做一个小演示，
I'm not going to live code the whole
我不打算全部编写代码
thing because that would not be
事情，因为那不是
excitingly boring that would just be
令人兴奋的无聊只是
plain stupidly boring so what I did is I
平淡无聊，所以我所做的就是我
did prepare all the code for it and I'm
确实为此准备了所有代码，而我
going to going to boringly get reset my
要无聊地重置我的
way through the code - and then walk
通过代码的方式-然后步行
through it so this is an application
通过它，所以这是一个应用程序
it's it's going to be available on
这将是可用的
github as well so you can check it out
github也一样，所以你可以检查出来
literally later on and there's a couple
从字面上看，有几个
of classes in here the API class is the
API类的类别是
main one there's a number of commands
主要的有很多命令
let's move to there's a couple of
让我们转到有几个
commands defined here so there's the
这里定义的命令
register bike command it's a bike rental
注册自行车命令，这是一辆自行车出租
application of course I'm since I'm
自从我申请以来
Dutch we do everything by bike we own
荷兰人，我们拥有的自行车会做的一切
one normally so we don't need to rent
通常一个，所以我们不需要租
but eh who cares i register a bike then
但是，谁在乎我当时要注册一辆自行车
I can rent that bike and I can return it
我可以租那辆自行车，还可以归还
right there's a bike itself which in
右边有一辆自行车
this case is in aggregates this is an
这种情况是合计的
action concept which is a consistency
动作概念是一致的
boundary of in this case only one entity
在这种情况下，只有一个实体的边界
but in general a number of entities
但总体上有许多实体
together I've also marked it with
一起我也用
identity to indicate this is in a
标识这是在
hibernate
冬眠的
sorry JP a entity and that is a
对不起，JP，是一个实体，这是一个
notification also for axon to say well I
通知还要求轴突说得好我
want to just store this aggregate as a
只想将此聚合存储为
JPA entity just in a database somewhere
JPA实体仅位于数据库中的某个位置
and it has a number of properties as an
它具有许多作为
ID a location and whoever rented the
标识一个地点，无论谁租了
bike could be null if it's not rented at
如果不租自行车，自行车可能为空
the moment there's a bunch of command
当下有一堆命令
handlers on it so I can register the
处理程序，以便我可以注册
bike that's a constructor so it creates
自行车是构造函数，因此它可以创建
a new bike and then if I have a bike I
一辆新自行车，然后如果我有一辆自行车我
can rent
可以租
or return it and it checks whether it
或将其退回，并检查是否
has already been rented out or not to
已经被出租或不出租
make sure that the logic works then we
确保逻辑有效，然后我们
have a query service that says I have a
有一个查询服务，说我有一个
query handler I can send a query like if
查询处理程序我可以发送查询，如
somebody wants to know give me all the
有人想知道给我所有
bikes then I will do a find all and this
自行车，那么我将尽一切所能
just delegates everything to a spring
只是把一切委托给春天
data JPA repository
数据JPA存储库
doesn't get any more boring than that I
没有比我更无聊的了
can I can do find one well the
我能找到一个很好的
application is empty the repository is
应用程序为空，存储库为
empty and then we have a controller just
空，然后我们有一个控制器
to make sure that we can interact with
确保我们可以与
this application but the controller
这个应用程序，但控制器
doesn't really invoke any of the
并没有真正调用任何
components directly so the difference
组件直接不同
here is that this component says I want
这是该组件说我想要
to send a command so when I do a put on
发送命令，所以当我穿上
a bike ID I do a command gateway dots
自行车ID我做了一个命令网关点
and register a bike with that ID and
并用该ID注册一辆自行车，并
that location this is fairly trivial to
那个位置对
the point where it's useless to do
毫无用处的地步
messaging like this and then but we can
这样的消息传递，但是我们可以
do some cooler stuff on the way so don't
在途中做一些更酷的事情，所以不要
give up just yet so I could run this
暂时放弃，这样我就可以运行
application you'll just have to trust me
您只需要信任我的应用程序
that it will work well don't trust me so
它会很好的运行不要相信我
let's run it
让我们运行它
I love that completion completion is a
我喜欢完成完成是一个
lot slower on stage than it is in
在舞台上比在舞台上慢很多
preparation all right so I can take my
准备好就可以拿走我的
SP requests right here and I can do i
SP要求在这里，我可以做到
can create a beck let's put it in
可以创造一个贝克，让我们把它放进去
barcelona loop now run it there you go
巴塞罗那循环现在在那儿运行
it says 1 2 3 4 it returns the
它说1 2 3 4它返回
identifier of the bike that we just
我们刚才的自行车的标识符
created
被创造
that's great now we can rent it out
太好了，现在我们可以租出去了
right so we can rent it let's say I pick
对，所以我们可以租它，假设我选择
it up
它起来
ok bike rented to a large fantastic
好的自行车租了一个很大的幻想
let's try to rent it by Stephen it's my
让我们尝试由史蒂芬租它是我的
colleague ha too late I got the bike
同事哈我来不及了自行车
already so let me return it - lets go
已经让我退回它-放手
for a ride right a return in Amsterdam
乘车返回阿姆斯特丹
well now Stephen is interested in
现在，斯蒂芬对
getting the bike not sure how he's
让自行车不确定他的状态
getting times to them that's his problem
给他们时间是他的问题
so the bike is rented nothing nothing
所以那辆自行车什么都没租
really special and where we can execute
真的很特别，我们可以执行
a query you could say what bikes do you
一个查询，你可以说你是什么自行车
have well great there's one bike that
很棒，有一辆自行车
was was in Amsterdam it was rented now
当时在阿姆斯特丹，现在被租了
by Stephen right there's nothing really
斯蒂芬说的没错
exciting about this stuff oops where's
这些东西令人兴奋哦
my there it is all right so that
我那里没事，所以
explicit mention the explicit messaging
明确提及明确讯息
just gives us the promise of I don't
只是给了我们我不的承诺
know location transparency but it's not
知道位置的透明度，但不是
really that valuable now those who know
那些知道的人真的很有价值
axon or those who don't accidently is a
轴突或那些不偶然的人是
framework that helps you build say large
可以帮助您建立很大的框架
scale or small scale doesn't really
规模或小规模并不是真的
matter that much but applications using
如此重要，但应用程序使用
the principles of domain driven design
域驱动设计原理
and securest and events sourcing now
现在最安全的事件采购
CQRS is who's not familiar with CQRS
CQRS是不熟悉CQRS的人
let's do a quick check those are very
让我们快速检查一下那些
few that's good
几个很好
so see caress is a very simple principle
所以看爱抚是一个很简单的原则
where you say I take an application a
你说我在哪里申请
nice
不错
the responsibility of that application
该应用程序的责任
into two parts one part is responsible
分为两个部分
for handling commands changes to my
用于处理我的命令更改
application and the other part is
应用程序，另一部分是
responsible for handling queries which
负责处理哪些查询
is to provide information about the
是为了提供有关
current state of the application right
申请权的当前状态
actually there's a form a level of CQRS
实际上有某种形式的CQRS
in any application that you have out
在您拥有的任何应用程序中
there right if you use a search engine
如果您使用搜索引擎，就在那里
that is a query model you're doing that
这是您正在执行的查询模型
to handle queries right that is a model
正确处理作为模型的查询
designed to handle specific types of
设计用于处理特定类型的
queries right typically rich text
通常对富文本进行查询
searches but there's also other types of
搜索，但还有其他类型的
Cruz that you can do with them
克鲁兹，你可以和他们一起做
so each of those areas will have a
因此，这些区域中的每个区域都会有一个
different model right a model that is
不同的模型对一个模型
focused on doing that part that it's
专注于做那是
responsible for so the command model is
负责，因此命令模型是
responsible for validating incoming
负责验证传入
requests and deciding what to do whereas
要求并决定要做什么，而
the projections are responsible for
投影负责
handling queries and providing an
处理查询并提供
information in a as efficiently as
信息有效
possible and the reason you want to our
您想要我们的可能和原因
M we use events to generally to make
M我们通常使用事件来
sure that when we execute a command we
确保当我们执行命令时
omit events to let the projections
省略事件以使投影
update themselves the reason why we
更新自己为什么我们
would want to do that is generally
通常想这样做
because the non-functional czar quite
因为无功能的沙皇相当
different on any of any part of the
在任何地方的任何地方都不同
system like the purple part might on the
像紫色部分一样的系统
left might be something that's really
离开也许是真的
complex right it's a very complex part
复杂的权利，这是一个非常复杂的部分
of the system and it's deployed very
系统的部署，
often not a very nice combination to
通常不是一个很好的组合
have so you want to definitely isolate
有，所以你想绝对隔离
that from the rest there's some other
其余的还有一些
examples and the one on the right might
例子和右边的一个可能
be a component that is pretty unstable
成为非常不稳定的组件
and it uses massive amounts of memory
而且它使用大量的内存
for whatever reason you probably want to
无论出于何种原因，您可能想要
be able to separate that out as well so
能够将其分开
that if that crashes it doesn't take
那如果崩溃的话就不用了
down everything else of course try to
顺理成章地尝试其他一切
fix the stability issues but that's I
解决稳定性问题，但这就是我
guess obvious now in the example I had
我在这个例子中现在猜想很明显
earlier that is a absolutely trivial
之前那绝对是微不足道的
example right it's the simplest
正确的例子，这是最简单的
application I could think of that shows
我能想到的应用程序显示
CQRS and even in that application
CQRS甚至在该应用程序中
already we see some accidental
我们已经看到一些意外
complexity
复杂
so imagine five minutes of work and you
因此，想象一下您需要工作五分钟
have your first accidental complexity
遇到第一次意外的复杂性
case imagine what happens if you start
想象一下如果开始
with continued working on that for for
继续为此工作
days on end and the problem is in the
连续几天，问题出在
bike class if we look at the bike the
自行车课，如果我们看一下自行车
way it's structured this is very nice
它的结构方式非常好
information for a view right this is the
正确的视图信息，这是
information we want when we do a query
查询时需要的信息
we want to know where a bike is and who
我们想知道自行车在哪里以及谁
has rented it at the moment right but to
目前已将其出租，但
execute commands to validate whether the
执行命令以验证是否
bike is rentable at the moment or not
现在是否可以租用自行车
there's way too much information right
信息太多了
so that information is useful for
这样信息对
queries but not for executing commands
查询但不用于执行命令
so what we can do is we can apply seek
所以我们能做的就是可以申请寻求
us to the application that we've just
我们到刚才的应用程序
built and what we need to do for that is
内置的，为此我们需要做的是
get reset you can do that in your own
重设，您可以自己做
projects of course not
项目当然不是
there we go yes I'm cheating I know I do
在那里，我们走了，我在作弊，我知道我在做
promised I did write all of the code
答应我确实写了所有代码
that's in here so what we do we split
就在这里，所以我们要做的是拆分
the command and the query so there's
命令和查询，所以有
different packages now right there's a
现在有不同的包装
command package hey there's our bike
命令包，嘿，有我们的自行车
again what does it look like now it's
再次看起来像现在
slightly different there's still an
稍有不同，仍然
entity it's an aggregate but now there's
实体，这是一个聚合，但现在有
just a boolean the boolean is the
只是布尔值，布尔值是
simplest form of data right it is the is
最简单的数据形式是
the atom of our of our data everything
我们数据的原子一切
else is just a bunch of bullying's in a
否则只是一堆欺凌
row in our API we added a few events
在我们的API中，我们添加了一些事件
because right now as part of our
因为现在作为我们的一部分
commands we start to emit events and
我们开始发出事件的命令
because this is a very simple
因为这很简单
application a a command results in a a
应用程序aa命令结果为aa
happens events but in a more production
发生事件，但产量更高
like systems more valuable systems those
像系统更有价值的系统
air commands and events tend to diverge
空中指挥和事件趋于分歧
somewhat and we have some query models
有点，我们有一些查询模型
and this one gives us the status of a
这给了我们一个状态
bike and here's the data that we had
骑自行车，这是我们拥有的数据
earlier the bike ID the location and the
较早的自行车ID的位置和
renter and this is now also an entity
承租人，这现在也是一个实体
and we have our projection class and
我们有我们的投影班
that does some interesting things let me
做一些有趣的事情让我
try to get
想拿到
some more space so what this does is it
一些更多的空间，所以它是做什么的
uses a spring data API a repository
在存储库中使用spring数据API
which is pretty boring thing just works
这很无聊
it gives you all the stuff you probably
它为您提供了所有可能的东西
need and it reacts to events and it says
需要，它对事件做出反应，并说
when a bike is registered I want to
当我注册自行车时，我想
register a new item of status when I get
当我得到一个新的状态项
a bike rented I'm going to find the bike
租了辆自行车我要去找自行车
that was rented and I'll put the renter
那是租来的，我把租人
in there this just does the simple
在那里，这只是简单的
simple updates and then there's some
简单的更新，然后有一些
query handlers that say well if you want
如果需要的话，查询处理程序说的很好
all of them we do a repository don't
所有这些我们都做一个仓库
find all the logic is pretty much the
发现所有逻辑都差不多
same but we've split the two models
相同，但我们将两种模型分开
there's now a command model focused on
现在有一个专注于命令模型
validating whether you're allowed to
验证您是否被允许
rent that bike and there's a query model
租那辆自行车，有一个查询模型
to tell you whether where the bike is or
告诉你自行车在哪里还是
who currently owns it that's all great
目前拥有它的人都很棒
but there's so much more so let's move
但是还有更多，让我们继续前进
on what you want me to run the
在你要我运行的
application I'm not sure what you said
我不知道你说什么
I'll just interpret it as a yes the
我只是将其解释为是
other one was still running
另一个仍在运行
now if you expect any other behavior I
现在，如果您期望其他任何行为，
really have to disappoint you because we
真的要让你失望，因为我们
haven't changed any behavior now the
现在还没有改变任何行为
thing is because of alter configuration
事情是因为更改配置
here with all the infrastructure that we
这里有我们所有的基础设施
need to get the commands to their
需要获得命令给他们
destination the events to publish to
将事件发布到的目的地
their destinations and even the queries
他们的目的地，甚至是查询
to their destinations there's nothing in
到他们的目的地，什么都没有
our application that has that type of
我们的应用程序具有
infrastructure right the infrastructure
基础设施对基础设施
is all also configured and also wired
也都已配置并接线
for us based on oops no based on the
对我们而言，基于糟糕，基于
availability of certain other
其他的可用性
dependencies right I mean in the end
到底我是说依赖
spring boot is mostly XML programming
spring boot 大部分是XML编程
right it's submit back to the whoops bit
正确，它会退回给人们
back to the spring one days where you
回到春天的那一天
just did a lot of XML then it works its
只是做了很多XML然后就可以了
the same with spring books but then you
春季书也一样，但是你
do it in the palm here we go we issue a
在这里，我们去做我们发出一个
bike we're not interested in I'm using
我们对使用的自行车不感兴趣
an in-memory database for these demo so
这些演示的内存数据库，因此
I issued my bike I'm renting it
我发行了我的自行车正在出租
fantastic Stephen wants to rent it
梦幻般的史蒂芬想租它
hooray it doesn't work right so nothing
万万没用，所以没事
nothing really changed it's just the
没有什么真正的改变，只是
same application again let's try to stop
再次使用同一应用程序，让我们尝试停止
it all right so we changed a lot of code
没关系，所以我们更改了很多代码
and nothing really happened right
真的什么都没发生
nothing really changed okay great we've
真的没有什么改变，好极了，我们已经
got we've got the hello world sample
我们有世界上最好的样本
right there's a lot of exciting stuff
对，有很多令人兴奋的东西
happening but we can't see that from the
发生了，但我们看不到
outside just yet because now we're
还在外面，因为现在我们在
publishing events and there's something
发布事件，有一些东西
special about events that commands and
关于命令和
queries don't have is that they remain
查询没有的是，它们仍然存在
valuable over time they they represent
随着时间的推移它们代表着宝贵的价值
they describe a facts that occurred and
他们描述了一个事实，
it might be valuable to remember that
记住这一点可能很有价值
our fact occurred a couple of days
我们的事实发生了几天
months maybe even years from now right
从现在起几个月甚至几年
there's also some challenges how can we
还有一些挑战，我们如何
guarantee that the publication of that
保证该出版物的发布
event and the storage of our entity new
事件和我们实体的存储新
entity States is an atomic operation how
实体国家是一个原子操作
can we guarantee that we did we had to
我们能否保证我们做到了
roll back the database transaction for
回滚数据库事务
some
一些
and did you get the events published
你把事件发布了吗
there's some solutions for that
有一些解决方案
yes but there's another thing about
是的，但是还有另一件事
events is that how can you guarantee
事件是你怎么能保证
that the events you omit is a truthful
您忽略的事件是真实的
representation of what happened in the
发生的事情的表示
past basically what we want is the truth
过去基本上我们想要的是事实
the whole truth and nothing but the
整个事实，除了
truth and if events are a side effect of
事实，以及事件是否是
what you're doing you cannot guarantee
你在做什么，你不能保证
this the events need to be the source of
这是事件的来源
everything right and if something
一切正常，如果有的话
happens it's in the source and if it
发生在源中，如果发生
didn't happen it's not that's the things
没有发生，不是那样的事情
we want so with events were saying we
我们想要这样的事件说
don't store the states as an example on
不要将状态存储为示例
the Left we don't store the fact that
左派我们不存储以下事实
currently that order has been returned
目前该订单已退回
as you can see in the bottom and it has
正如您在底部看到的那样
one item of a luxury the chair but with
一件豪华椅子，但
the event sourcing you get the hand tire
采购活动时您会得到手轮胎
history you get the it was created two
历史，你得到它被创建两个
items were added one item was removed in
项目已添加，其中一项已删除
order was confirmed and it was shipped
订单已确认并已发货
then it was canceled and that's why we
然后它被取消了，这就是为什么我们
had to wait for the return shipment
必须等待回运
because somebody cancelled it after it
因为之后有人取消了
was shipped and then we've got the
被运了，然后我们得到了
shipment now there's some information in
现在发货中有一些信息
there that we have lost on the left
在那边我们迷路了
right of course we can generate that as
当然，我们可以将其生成为
a side effect that information somewhere
信息在某处的副作用
in logs for example but it's very hard
例如在日志中，但是很难
to guarantee that those logs are
以确保这些日志是
absolutely correct so in the case of
绝对正确，因此
event sourcing we don't have the stuff
活动采购我们没有东西
on the left anymore if you want to know
如果您想知道就在左侧
what the current state of an aggregate
聚合的当前状态是什么
is we need to replay its history so the
是我们需要重播它的历史，所以
value of event sourcing is in the fact
事实上，事件来源的价值
that you've got an audit trail you know
您已经了解了审计线索
exactly what happened in your
你到底发生了什么
application it's very powerful to do
应用程序，功能非常强大
analytics later on right it also helps
稍后再进行分析也有帮助
to improve the modeling if you if you
如果您愿意，可以改善建模
get the hang of events or saying you'll
掌握事件或说你​​会
find that it's much it's a much more
发现更多很多
natural way to reason about the logic of
关于逻辑的自然推理方式
an application especially in the command
一个应用程序，特别是在命令中
model it's a lot simpler to say well in
模型，说得好得多
this case I do this validation and then
在这种情况下，我进行验证，然后
I decide this
我决定这个
happened that's it right you you've got
碰巧就是你拥有了
an explicit record of something
明确的记录
happening instead of an implicit record
发生而不是隐式记录
where you say well the state changes
你说得好地方状态会改变
these changes mean that this happened
这些变化意味着发生了这种情况
right it all becomes very explicit and
对，这一切变得非常明确，
they are very nice to test you can use
他们很好测试可以使用
given when then style testing with event
在进行事件样式测试时给出
sourcing saying given some events in the
采购说在
past when I execute a certain command I
当我执行某个命令时，过去
expect more events or maybe no events I
希望有更多事件，或者我没有事件
expect an exception of validation
期望验证例外
exceptions something like that but
像这样的例外
there's one one more thing
还有一件事
and that event sourcing gives you the
而事件源给您
power of not now and that is a very
现在的力量，这是一个非常
powerful thing because we always want
强大的东西，因为我们一直想要
everything done or we are forced to get
一切都做完了，否则我们被迫去做
everything done by sometime right how
在某个时候完成的所有事情
nice would it be if we could just say
好吧，如果我们只能说
yes we can do this but we don't have to
是的，我们可以做到这一点，但我们不必
do it now we can do it when it becomes
现在就做，当它变成
important I had a customer a while ago
重要的是我之前有一个客户
and he said we need to make sure we
他说我们需要确保我们
capture all of the data for reporting oh
捕获所有数据以进行报告哦
that's interesting what kind of reports
有趣的是什么样的报告
do you want to run I don't know
你想跑步吗我不知道
then how am I going to prepare anything
那我要怎么准备
for those reports but I said don't worry
对于那些报告，但我说不要担心
you can go find out what kind of reports
你可以去找出什么样的报告
you want you can come back to me and
你想你可以回到我身边
I'll do nothing with that information it
这些信息我什么也不会做
was like what do you mean I don't care I
就像你是什么意思我不在乎我
don't care what information you think
不在乎你在想什么信息
you'll want because we capture
您会想要的，因为我们捕获了
everything we have to capture and
我们必须捕获的一切，
anything we capture right now we can we
我们现在捕获的任何东西我们都可以
can create the report for you from the
可以从
day we launched this product in in
那天我们在
production and he didn't believe me he
生产，他不相信我，他
checked up several times and then there
检查了几次，然后在那里
was finally this moment where they
终于在这一刻，他们
wanted some some data dump in some
想要一些数据转储
specific formats for analytics later on
稍后用于分析的特定格式
and we were of course able to provide
我们当然能够提供
that so now that we have an application
所以现在我们有了一个应用程序
that's emitting offense let's see what
冒犯了我们看看
it takes to do event sourcing yes I know
需要进行事件采购是的，我知道
this is how you do within sourcing
这就是您在采购中的做法
so let's see what changed so let's start
让我们看看发生了什么变化，让我们开始
here API nothing changed right the same
这里的API没什么改变吧
command same events or half is off the
命令相同的事件或一半关闭
screen but you'll have to trust me on
屏幕，但您必须信任我
that the bike status by projection
通过投影得知自行车的状态
nothing changed these still rely on the
没有改变，这些仍然依靠
same events the only real change is in
同一事件中唯一真正的变化是
the bike the structure of how we built
自行车的结构
the bike and we still have that boolean
自行车，我们还有那个布尔值
field is available but you can see
字段可用，但您可以看到
there's the @ entity annotation is now
现在有@实体注释
missing that is enough to tell action I
缺失足以告诉我行动
have the intent to event source this
有意图事件来源
thing you do not need to store its state
你不需要存储其状态的东西
anywhere and it becomes default to use
任何地方，它成为默认使用
event sourcing we use an aggregate
事件采购我们使用汇总
identifier we could have stayed on the
标识符，我们本可以留在
JPA ID but we don't need JPA in this
JPA ID，但是我们不需要JPA
class anymore so when we register a bike
上课了，所以当我们注册自行车时
we're going to apply an event because in
我们将应用一个事件，因为
this case there's no validation for
这种情况下没有验证
registration of a bike which is maybe
可能是自行车的注册
not realistic but let's stick to that as
不现实，但我们坚持
an example and in here we just make a
一个例子，在这里我们只做一个
decision ok we want to handle the rent
好的，我们要处理租金
by command we want to rent out rent out
根据命令，我们要出租
the bike the only thing we need to do is
自行车，我们唯一需要做的就是
check if it's available if it's not we
如果不是，请检查是否可用
throw an exception if it is then we have
如果是的话抛出一个异常
decided that the bike was rented out and
决定把自行车租出去
then you apply those two things that
然后你把这两件事
stages this event for publication to
将此事件发布到
other components right no to the stages
舞台上没有其他组件
it's not there yet it's ready to go out
还没到那里就可以出去了
and it also invokes the methods below
并且还会调用以下方法
which are the events sourcing handlers
这是事件源处理程序
and this is a very important concept in
这是一个非常重要的概念
an event sourcing and it has nothing to
一个事件源，它没有什么可做的
do with axon conceptually if you use
从概念上讲，使用轴突
event sourcing you have to be able to
活动采购，您必须能够
reconstruct the if the bike states in
如果自行车在
this case based off of its historical
本案基于其历史
events right no validation the things
事件没事就没事了
happened you do not validate anything
碰巧你什么都不验证
that happened in the past you can
过去发生过的你可以
dislike it but that does need not mean
不喜欢它，但这并不意味着
you do not have to act on it so if a
您不必对此采取行动，因此，如果
bike was registered grades then we said
自行车是注册成绩，然后我们说
the bike ID to bike ID and we set the
自行车ID到自行车ID，我们将
fact that it's available right if a bike
如果有自行车就可以使用
was registered it becomes available for
已注册，可用于
rent if the bike was returned it's
如果退还那辆自行车，租金是
available and if a bike was rented it's
可用，如果租了一辆自行车
not available this is the only thing we
不可用，这是我们唯一的事情
care about there might be hundreds of
关心可能有数百个
other events we don't care about them in
其他我们不在乎的事件
this specific aggregate so the apply
这个特定的总和，因此适用
done not only stages this event for
不仅为该事件上演了
publication it will also ensure that
发布它还将确保
method is invoked and it's invoked
方法被调用并且被调用
directly so on the line of code after
直接在代码行之后
apply you have the state changes that
应用你有状态改变
are described in the apply method so
在apply方法中进行了说明
there's no async difficult programming
没有异步困难的编程
involved now there's also one thing that
现在涉及到的还有一件事
I changed which is kind of hidden there
我改变了那种隐藏在那里
are some dependencies here there's an
有一些依赖关系，这里有一个
axon spring boot starter in the other
轴突弹簧启动启动器在另一个
examples I just excluded the axon server
我只是排除了轴突服务器
connector there's a new component that
连接器中有一个新组件
we have since late last year called
自去年下半年以来，我们已经致电
axonal server
轴突服务器
it's like axon there's a there's an open
就像是轴突，那里有一个开放的地方
source version of that that you can you
您可以的原始版本
can just get there's a docker container
可以得到一个码头集装箱
for it which I'm running here in the
为此，我正在这里运行
demo as well and in this case I did not
演示以及在这种情况下，我没有
exclude the connector anymore so that
排除连接器，以便
the author configuration of spring boots
春靴的作者配置
will connect the application to axonal
将应用程序连接到轴突
server running on the local host because
服务器在本地主机上运行，​​因为
from now on I don't want to lose the
从现在开始，我不想失去
state of my application anymore so let's
我的应用程序的状态了，所以让我们
start this
开始这个
great it's probably running and let's
很好，它可能正在运行，让我们
that's the downside of reset you have to
那是重置的缺点
make your changes what do we put it this
做出更改，我们该怎么做
time Madrid
时间马德里
whoops why not there we go we issued a
哎呀，为什么不在那里，我们去了，我们发出了
bike now and of course the behavior is
现在骑自行车，当然，行为是
not any different I can still rent this
没什么不同我还是可以租这个
bike and it's bike rented nothing in the
自行车，这辆自行车在
behavior changed it's just the way we
行为改变，这就是我们的方式
execute the behavior and there's still
执行该行为，仍然存在
some validation here and let's return it
在这里进行一些验证，让我们返回它
in where are we returning the bike ok
在哪里我们还车好
we're cycling through Barcelona why not
我们在巴塞罗那骑自行车，为什么不
and then Stephen takes it in Barcelona
然后史蒂芬把它带到巴塞罗那
great so now we've got some events and
太好了，现在我们有一些活动，
every time I execute a command my
每次我执行命令
application loads all of these events
应用程序加载所有这些事件
regenerates the bike to check whether
重新生成自行车以检查是否
the new command is it's valid right so
新命令是正确的，所以
we can go to this page this is the the
我们可以转到此页面，这是
axon server dashboard and we can see
轴突服务器仪表板，我们可以看到
that there's one application running
有一个正在运行的应用程序
it's connected to this this server and
它已连接到此服务器，
we there we go we can search for the
我们去那里我们可以搜索
events in here we see that there's four
我们在这里看到的事件有四个
events that have happened some very nice
发生的事情非常好
XML structure we'll ignore that for now
XML结构，我们暂时将其忽略
but we can see some stuff happened to
但是我们可以看到发生了一些事情
this specific bike one two three four in
这个特定的自行车一二三四在
the in the past all right so now we've
过去好吧，现在我们已经
got event sourcing going we can do some
进行活动采购我们可以做一些
more exciting stuff so again there's not
更令人兴奋的东西，所以再次没有
much infrastructure code that I had to
我必须要做的很多基础架构代码
do it's just because I want to do if in
只是因为我想在
sourcing I just need to read structure
采购我只需要阅读结构
my bike aggregates and the rest of the
我的自行车和其余的
application just works the same ways and
应用程序的工作方式相同，
everything everything is auto wire
一切都是自动线
there's no exciting configuration that
没有令人兴奋的配置
we need to to do now one of the
我们现在需要做的其中一项
advantages so I told you about the power
优点，所以我告诉你有关力量
of not now right
现在不正确
so that has to do with the fact that you
所以这与事实有关
have the events that are stored and as
具有已存储的事件并作为
new events are stored you have this
新事件存储，你有这个
event handler reacting to it right so I
事件处理程序对此做出正确的反应，所以我
can I can query the bike status and it
我可以查询自行车的状态吗？
will keep them to give me an updated
会让他们给我更新
status of of the of the bikes so every
自行车的状态，所以每一个
time there's an event we just update it
时间有一个事件，我们只是更新它
but what we can do now is we can create
但是我们现在可以做的是
a new event handler we can create a new
一个新的事件处理程序，我们可以创建一个新的
projection if we want and have that
如果我们想要并拥有投影
start up day zero and then move its way
从零开始，然后继续前进
forward and hopefully one day it will
向前，希望有一天它将
catch up so let's do that let's
赶上，让我们做到这一点，让我们
implement a new projection and yes I'm
实施新的预测，是的，我是
going to do it that way again and I'll
再次这样做，我会
just run you through the code that has
只是通过具有
changed so right now we just created a
改变了，所以现在我们刚刚创建了一个
new package history and there's a new
新的包装历史，还有一个新的
projection and it's pretty similar but
投影，它非常相似，但是
it's there's still that information
仍然有信息
there's still the bike ID there's a
仍然有自行车ID，还有一个
description of what happened and there's
关于发生了什么的描述
a timestamp on when it happened right
正确的时间戳记
now we didn't record a timestamp on our
现在我们没有在我们的记录时间戳
events so let's hope that works out and
事件，让我们希望能解决这个问题，
then we have our projection that just
然后我们有一个预测
handles all of these events right it's a
处理所有这些事件，这是一个
spring component there's some event
春季部分有一些事件
handlers and says oh if the bike was
经理说哦，如果自行车是
registered and we can put a timestamp
注册，我们可以加盖时间戳
because we're interested in knowing when
因为我们有兴趣知道何时
actually this happened right so great we
实际上这发生的太好了，我们
can launch this application
可以启动这个应用程序
let's stop this one
让我们停止这个
and now because the there's still actual
现在因为那里仍然是真实的
server running in the background we
服务器在后台运行
still have these events right so now the
仍然有这些事件，所以现在
application is starting and it will have
应用程序正在启动，它将具有
this historical information still in
这些历史信息仍在
there so this component is going to
在那里，这个组件将
chase the head of the stream right away
立即追赶溪流的头
so we can do is in the requests we have
所以我们可以做的就是在我们的请求中
a history call for bike one two three
历史悠久的自行车一二三
four and we can see exactly what
四，我们可以确切地看到
happened so this is the new model that
发生了，所以这是新的模型
we have created and yes it's slightly
我们已经创建了，是的
boring in this case but I promised you
在这种情况下很无聊，但我答应过你
boring we can see that bike 1 2 3 4 was
很无聊，我们可以看到自行车1 2 3 4是
registered in Madrid on oh that was a
在马德里注册的哦
few minutes ago well and then was rented
几分钟前好，然后被租了
out yeah we went to it was returned in
是的，我们去了它返回了
Barcelona and then Stephan rented it
巴塞罗那，然后斯蒂芬租了下来
right so we can create a new model and
对，所以我们可以创建一个新模型，
not worry about anything we need to
不用担心我们需要做的任何事情
replay this is just by itself this is
重看这仅仅是它本身
just by doing nothing you get a replay
只是无所事事就可以重播
for free all right let's go quickly to
免费，好吧，让我们快速前往
the last entry so now we have this
最后一个条目，所以现在我们有了这个
really exciting quote-unquote system
真正令人兴奋的报价-取消报价系统
well we've got commands and events and
好吧，我们有命令和事件，
queries going round where there's all
查询到处都是
these messages floating and everything
这些消息浮动，一切
is nice and streaming and then we have
很好，流媒体，然后我们有
this stupid HTTP calls to get that
这个愚蠢的HTTP调用来获得那个
information like polling information
诸如轮询信息之类的信息
right wouldn't it be nice to say well
对吧，说得好不好
let's stream this stuff all the way to
让我们把这些东西一直流到
the front end right I mean we have
前端对，我是说我们有
spring wet flux nowadays so why not use
如今春季湿润的助焊剂，为什么不使用
that to make it streaming now there's a
要使其流式传输，现在有一个
few ways to go about and my initial
几种方法和我最初的
naive reaction when we started streaming
开始流式传输时幼稚的反应
stuff to the UI was to say well we've
用户界面的意思是说我们已经
got an event handler that receives an
有一个事件处理程序接收
event why not just stream that event all
事件为什么不只是流所有事件
the way to use interface and let that
使用界面的方式，并让
update itself there's a bit of a problem
更新自身存在一些问题
there because the event handler is
在那里，因为事件处理程序是
probably updating some information and
可能会更新一些信息，
it has logic on how to update the
它具有有关如何更新
information based on the events
基于事件的信息
now we would have to duplicate that
现在我们将不得不重复
logic in the user interface it is very
用户界面中的逻辑非常
likely that the user interface is
用户界面可能是
written in another programming language
用另一种编程语言编写
then your back-end since we are the
那么您的后端，因为我们是
spring conference this is not the nodejs
春季会议，这不是nodejs
IO right so since that event handler is
IO是正确的，所以既然该事件处理程序是
already updating information it has this
已经更新了信息
bike ID location rental properties and
自行车ID位置出租物业和
it's updating the fact that Stephen was
这更新了一个事实，斯蒂芬
now the renter in Barcelona so why not
现在是巴塞罗那的房客，为什么不呢
stream that message that we are using in
流式传输我们正在使用的消息
the queries anyway that structure why
无论如何查询结构
not send that as an updates and there's
不发送作为更新，并且有
a concept in an axon called subscription
轴突中的一个概念称为订阅
queries you can query for something say
查询您可以查询说些什么
give me or keep me up to date on the
给我或让我保持最新
bike 1 2 3 4 so let's do that let's see
自行车1 2 3 4，所以让我们来看看
what it what we need to do to get that
我们需要做些什么才能做到这一点
working so the biggest difference is
工作，所以最大的区别是
right now in our projection in the bike
现在在我们对自行车的投影中
history projection we want to subscribe
我们想要订阅的历史记录
to the history of a bike right so if
对自行车的历史，所以如果
something happens to that bike we want
我们想要的那辆自行车发生了什么
to be notified immediately so we have an
立即得到通知，因此我们有一个
update emitter that we can we also wire
更新我们可以连接的发射器
that into our projection and then we say
进入我们的投影，然后我们说
when a bike is rented we emit if
租自行车时，如果
something that somebody is interested in
某人感兴趣的东西
the location history we omit this events
我们忽略此事件的位置记录
and we say if the bike ID equals the
我们说如果自行车ID等于
payloads of the message for what this M
消息的有效负载为此M
is so great I'm lost
太好了我迷路了
so are you fantastic basically we're
所以你真的很棒吗
emitting and we're saying if if
发射，我们说如果
somebody's really interested in the bike
有人对自行车真的很感兴趣
ID that the current event represents
当前事件代表的ID
then we're going to send them the
然后我们将发送给他们
updates the M by the way is the query
通过查询方式更新M
and the payload of the query is the bike
查询的有效载荷是自行车
ID in in our case and if we look on the
本例中的ID，如果我们查看
other side we have
另一边
our controller and we added a method
我们的控制器，我们添加了一个方法
called mystery watch we can watch a bike
叫做神秘手表，我们可以看自行车
ID and it says you get a you do a
ID并说您得到了
subscription query you get a response
订阅查询得到响应
and on that response you can say I want
然后您可以说我想要
to the initial result and then the
到初始结果，然后
initial result is ammonia and it
最初的结果是氨，它
contains a list or at least an iterable
包含一个列表或至少一个可迭代的
of the initial bikes that or the initial
最初的自行车或最初的自行车
history that we have on this bike and we
我们在这辆自行车上的历史，我们
want to turn that into a flux so that we
希望将其转化为流量，以便我们
can concatenate that flux with any
可以将通量与任何
updates that we get and we just return
我们得到的更新，我们只是返回
that flux we just returned the flux of
我们刚刚返回的通量
bike history elements and we say this
自行车历史元素，我们这样说
produces an event stream right so what
产生一个事件流，那么
we can do
我们可以做的
whoops we need to start the application
糟糕，我们需要启动该应用程序
running out of time here
时间不多了
yes so now we got information and it's
是的，所以现在我们有了信息，这是
still wiggling around there so we need
还在那附近摇摆所以我们需要
to get one two three four back somewhere
一二三四回到某个地方
quickly let's go to our HTTP requests
快让我们转到我们的HTTP请求
and find return return return
并找到return return return
let's return it to Barcelona okay back
让我们回到巴塞罗那吧
return in Barcelona let's go back yes
返回巴塞罗那让我们回去是
return in Barcelona so it's just
返回巴塞罗那，所以
streaming this information live to do
实时流化此信息以做
this this front end so that's fairly
这个前端，这相当
simple so far now we've got about eight
到目前为止，到目前为止，我们只有八个
minutes left and that is plenty of time
还剩几分钟，这是很多时间
to take a big bowl of monolithic thing
拿一大碗整体的东西
to microservices because in that journey
微服务，因为在那段旅程中
I've spent almost all of our time
我几乎花了我们所有的时间
getting there so please stick around
到达那里，所以请坚持
because we're going to finish the entire
因为我们要完成整个
journey right fortunately doing that is
幸运的是，这样做是
not extremely complex so conceptually
在概念上不是很复杂
what we have right now is a monolith and
我们现在拥有的是一个整体
there's excellent framework handling all
有一个出色的框架可以处理所有
the messaging between these components
这些组件之间的消息传递
and what we need to do is scale that out
我们需要做的就是扩大规模
I did that last year here on this stage
我去年在这个舞台上做的
- yeah actually and last year I did that
-是的，去年我做到了
with an event server based on my sequel
基于我的续集的事件服务器
and Netflix spring cloud Netflix for for
和Netflix Spring Cloud Netflix for
discovery and we used RabbitMQ and trust
发现，我们使用RabbitMQ和信任
me that was not boring that was from my
不无聊的我
perspective pretty exciting because I
观点很令人兴奋，因为我
had two minutes left
还有两分钟
to get stuff fixed that is not the kind
修理不是那种东西
of thing we want to in production so
我们想要生产的东西
what I'm going to do now instead is and
我现在要做的是
this is something we didn't have last
这是我们最后没有的东西
year to use actual server in in its
在其实际使用服务器的年份
place so we can just distribute that now
的地方，所以我们现在就可以分发
this is actually a very simple change
这实际上是一个非常简单的更改
because the only thing we are doing is
因为我们唯一要做的就是
using spring profiles I'm not actually
使用弹簧型材我不是
separating the logic into different
将逻辑分为不同的
components but you're all spring experts
组件，但您都是春季专家
so you'll have to trust me that if I put
所以你要相信我，如果我放
at profile command that this beam will
在配置文件命令中，该光束将
only be considered when
仅在以下情况下考虑
the command profile is active right
命令配置文件处于活动状态
there's another these classes have their
还有另一类这些课程
history profile on them right history
他们的历史档案正确的历史
profile and we have the query profile on
配置文件，我们在查询配置文件
those and now what we can do have to get
这些，现在我们能做的就是
out of presentation mode otherwise I
退出演示模式，否则我
can't find my run configuration I'm
找不到我的跑步配置
going to start all of these components
将开始所有这些组件
so I'm going to start the command part
所以我要开始命令部分
the query parts and the UI parts as
查询部分和UI部分为
separate applications it's going to
单独的应用程序
start three applications as you can see
如您所见，启动三个应用程序
in the bottom and they all have
在底部，他们都有
different responsibilities right so this
不同的责任，所以这
is a generally genuinely
通常是真正的
distributed system on the localhost but
本地主机上的分布式系统，但是
at least there's inter-process
至少存在过程间
communication going on so so let's see
沟通正在进行中，所以让我们来看看
what happens
怎么了
should be able to do that subscription
应该能够进行订阅
query again if everything starts
再次查询是否一切开始
well this is what you get
好吧，这就是你得到的
fantastic this is what I love about
太棒了，这就是我喜欢的
demos this is the exciting part of where
演示这是其中令人兴奋的部分
it should be boring something happened
应该很无聊
and I do not know what I would love to
而且我不知道我想做什么
save worked on my machine but this is
保存在我的机器上工作，但这是
also my machine so it should just work
还有我的机器，所以它应该可以正常工作
all right let's try again let's try
好的，让我们再试一次
something simpler just do an HTTP
更简单的方法就是执行HTTP
request so I've also got a generates it
请求，所以我也有生成它
just says generate them all twenty is a
只是说生成它们全部二十就是一个
bit of a bit much let's generate two
让我们生成两个
bikes that are rented out three times
租了三遍的自行车
each does that work hopefully does no
每个工作都希望不会
exceptions no exceptions great and now
例外，没有例外，很棒，现在
we should be able to see the bikes yes
我们应该可以看到自行车了
so we've still got messaging going on
所以我们仍然有消息传递
there's now that one bike that we
现在有一辆自行车，
created earlier and there's the two
较早创建，有两个
bikes are just generated and let's move
自行车刚刚产生，让我们开始
on quickly so because there's one more
很快就开始了，因为还有一个
thing one really really boring I promise
我保证我真的很无聊
this is the most boring of everything
这是所有事情中最无聊的
that we want to do so now we've got this
现在我们想要这样做
distributed system right there's
分布式系统
components communicating and imagine
组件进行交流和想象
we're going to scale this there's going
我们将要扩展这一点
to be more components as we promised we
像我们承诺的那样成为更多组件
would have going on this journey to
本来会去
microservices and then there's gonna be
微服务，然后会有
more instances of these components and
这些组件的更多实例，以及
they're gonna be everywhere right we've
他们将无处不在，我们已经
got requests coming in they send
他们收到了请求
commands to some components they send
发送给某些组件的命令
events to other components that react by
其他组件做出反应的事件
sending queries to other components that
向其他组件发送查询
then send commands yet to other
然后发送命令给其他人
components that send queries and we get
发送查询的组件，我们得到
this really nice things causes things
这真好事会导致事情
causes things we need to get some
导致我们需要一些东西
information out of this mess right we
从这个烂摊子中获取信息吧
need to find a way to get an overview of
需要找到一种方法来概述
how this we need to trace the calls
我们如何跟踪电话
right so how do we do that Oh
对，那我们该怎么做哦
tracing right so let's implement that
跟踪正确，所以让我们实现它
and I could have done this by hand but
我本可以手工完成的，但是
given there's only two minutes fifty on
鉴于只有两分钟五十
clock I'm going to cheat again but I
时钟，我要再次作弊，但我
promise that I have only changed what
保证我只改变了什么
did I change here I only changed this I
我在这里改变了吗我只改变​​了我
added two dependencies if you don't
如果不添加两个依赖项
trust me that spring Buddha's XML
相信我，春天佛陀的XML
programming I think this is proof so
编程我认为这就是证明
I've got Jaeger running in a docker
我让Jaeger在docker中运行
container on the background and right
容器在背景和右边
now I can restart my applications using
现在我可以使用重新启动我的应用程序
this tracing of all slurps that's not
并非所有这些喝的追踪
what I wanted to do I will restart all
我想做的是重新启动所有
my applications
我的申请
and if you imagine the things you would
如果你想像那些事情，你会
need to do to get tracing working
需要做的才能跟踪工作
properly is setting all sorts of headers
正确地设置各种标题
in requests and making sure that these
在请求中，并确保这些
headers are passed along and then
头传递，然后
interpret it on the other side you need
在您需要的另一面进行解释
to report spans you need to start and
报告跨度，您需要开始
stop them so there's a lot of stuff
阻止他们，所以有很多东西
going on but we don't care no I do not
继续，但我们不在乎不，我不
want you please go away I love it when
想要你走开我爱它的时候
you do demos all right so let's generate
您可以进行演示，让我们生成
some some stuff again and make sure that
再来一些东西，并确保
some traces are Jana are created all
一些痕迹是贾纳创建的
right so we can go to local host slips
对的，所以我们可以去当地的寄宿单
so Jaeger UI yeah there's a generate
所以Jaeger UI是的，
data operation and there it is
数据操作，那里
well twelve hundred and sixty one spans
1261跨度
I think I over did it a bit but here's a
我想我做了一点，但这是一个
nice trace
不错的踪迹
do you have traces like that in
你有这样的痕迹吗
production I hope not
我希望不要生产
why well you can see here there's a
为什么你可以看到这里有一个
bunch of parallel instructions and
一堆并行指令和
that's because I did not change this
那是因为我没有改变
setting after doing my git reset so it
我的git reset之后设置
generated 20 bikes with ten rentals each
产生了20辆自行车，每辆十辆
and every rental happens after the
并且每笔租金都发生在
previous one but it's all caused by this
上一个，但这全是因为这个
one API call that I did so now you get
我做了一个API调用，现在您得到了
full tracing of all the commands you can
可以完全跟踪所有命令
see that the query component handles the
看到查询组件处理
events that came out of it you've got
从中产生的事件
everything and everything is just alter
一切都在改变
boringly auto configured for you so that
无聊自动为您配置，以便
was the tracing and with ten minutes on
是追踪，并持续了十分钟
the clock I would say please try it for
我要说的时钟请尝试一下
yourself you can check out the code on
你自己，你可以签出代码
that github repository you can cheat
你可以作弊的github存储库
your way through like I did just get
就像我刚得到的那样
reset your way through and if you have
重置您的方式，如果您有
any questions I will take them after the
任何问题，我将在
presentation thank you
演示文稿谢谢
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]